This ride will be the death of you.
Final Destination 3 is a horror, mystery film directed by James Wong.
High school senior Wendy's premonition of a deadly rollercoaster ride saves her life and a lucky
few, but not from death itself — which seeks out those who escaped their fate.
Wendy Christensen, played by Mary Elizabeth Winstead.
Kevin Fischer, played by Ryan Merriman.
Ian McKinley, played by Kris Lemche.
Erin, played by Alexz Johnson.
Frankie Cheeks, played by Sam Easton.
Jason Wise, played by Jesse Moss.
Final Destination 3 is a 2006 American supernatural horror film produced and
directed by James Wong, who co-wrote it with Glen Morgan.
It is a standalone sequel to Final Destination 2 (2003) and the
third installment in the Final Destination film series.
It stars Mary Elizabeth Winstead and Ryan Merriman, and
takes place six years after the first film.
Winstead plays Wendy Christensen, a high school graduate who has a premonition
that a roller coaster she and her classmates are riding will derail.
Although she saves some of them, Death begins hunting the survivors.
Wendy realizes that photographs she took at the
attraction contain clues about the deaths.
With survivor and friend Kevin Fischer (Merriman), Wendy tries to use this
knowledge to save the rest of the survivors and stop Death's scheme.
The film's development began shortly after the release of Final Destination 2; Jeffrey Reddick,
creator of the franchise and a co-writer of the first two films, did not return.
Unlike the second film, which was a direct sequel to the first, the
producers envisioned Final Destination 3 as a standalone film.
The idea of featuring a roller coaster derailment as the opening-scene
disaster came from New Line Cinema executive Richard Bryner.
From the beginning, Wong and Morgan saw control as a major theme in the film.
Casting began in March 2005 and concluded in April.
Like the previous two installments, it was filmed in Vancouver, Canada.
The first two weeks of the three-month shoot were spent filming
the scenes involving the roller coaster derailing.
Following its premiere at Grauman's Chinese Theatre on February 2, 2006, the film
was released in cinemas in the United States on February 10, 2006.
The DVD, released on July 25, 2006, includes commentaries,
documentaries, a deleted scene and an animated video.
A special-edition DVD called "Thrill Ride Edition" includes a feature called "Choose Their Fate", which acts as an interactive
film, allowing viewers to make decisions at specific points in the film that alter the course of the story.
Final Destination 3 received mixed reviews from critics.
The film was a financial success and, with box office receipts of nearly $118
million, the highest-grossing installment in the franchise at the time.
A fourth film, The Final Destination, was released in August 2009.
The film explores themes of dying and death, stroke of
fate, beheading, omen, premonition.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.